

JOHN ZHAO

Location: Los Gatos, CA 95032 Email: <u>john.zhao@sunvalle.net</u> Contact: 408-621-2926

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

More than 28 years of hands-on experiences in computing System, Application, Networking, Security and programming environments, lead large-scale technical projects, working with internal staff and vendors to define requirements, scope technical efforts, determine solutions, and then implement those solutions. Expert technical skills in UNIX/Linux Systems/Application build/support and development large DC on-prem/Cloud VPC integration laaS, PaaS, laC, docker/Jenkins /k8s CI/CD/Automation with Terraform/Ansible on KVM/AWS/GCP/Azure, Python(OS/System/DB/Web Interfaces/networking/automation/data science integration, Critial data encryption/recovery, Hard-working, good team management, self-motivated, well-organized and able to work effectively under pressure on demanding environment.

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

GitLab / GitHub / Jenkins / CI / CD/ Cloudformation /Terraform / Ansible, Kubernetes / Docker, UNIX / Linux /Windows/MacOS/WinAD-SFU, Oracle / MySQL / SQL, LDAP / KDC / NIS / IPA, SAN / NAS/Transparent Proxy, Strong Bash Shell Scripting with C/C++ / Python Package management, J2SE / J2EE /Apache / TLS, SQL / PL / SQL, Jumpstart / Kickstart / KVM, Grafana / Splunk / Data Dog/ Dynatrace

HOBBY & INTEREST

Classical Guitar | HiFi Audio

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION AND CERTIFICATION:

- Southeast University, China B.E. Electromagnetism Field & Microwave 1986-1990
- San Diego State University, California USA B.S. Computer Science 1992-1996
- Caltech Post Graduate Program in DevOps 2022 Mar-Dec

Other: Singapore Citizen | US Green Card holder

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sunvalley Computer Inc. (02/1999 to present) System Software Engineer – Lead SRE/DevOps Bay Area, California, United States & Singapore

- Invented Zero Trust DevOps Automation (High secure Crytocurrency level)
- System Software Engineer Lead SRE/DevOps/IT Engineering consulting for US custormer
- C++/Python, AI, Data science, docker-compose on Dev & Jenkins, K8s, Java, next.js,nodejs, AWS cli, terraform, ansible CI/CD on DevOps



Consulting supported Clients: Sun Mirosystems, NUS/NTU Com Center, Agilent, NEC, Visa Internationl, DBS Vickers, Orange(French Telecom), Converge Asia, Trend Micro, Polaris Wireless E911, Walmat Labs, Samgsumg SSD R&D labs, Oracle Cloud, Finicast, Apple BI, Cigna

Kroger (04/2019 to 02/2022)

Sr. Software Engineer – Lead SRE/DevOps

San Jose, California, United States

 Software Development on E-commerce Tech Innovation with SDLC lead DevOps and Python Back-end Support on GCP Gmap API services with auto-drive/delivery routing, AI/ML/Crypto market Simulation platform and tools & Azure Cloud - Application Servers, KDC, Bastion access gateway, 1Password/SSH-Key token environment. C/C++ and Python based products

HGST (04/2011 to 11/2015)

Principal Engineer (Cloud Solution)

San Jose, California, United States

Managing IBM Professional Services on HGST support DCE/DFS and IBM AFS environment, creating Linux & AWS
Cloud as replacement of IBM AIX legacy systems. Invented Virtual Encrypted Domain Prototype with open source
& LDAP, Kerberos KDC principal

Trident Microsystems Inc. (04/2008 to 03/2011) **Engineering On-Premise Platform Solution**

Santa Clara, California, United States

- Creating high secured engineering design network, protecting internal IP data & repo access for Santa Clara & Munich including Data cernter servers, engineering networks, applications and security, single-sign-on nis/ldap
- Deploy Solaris/Linux server/VM from command line & bash script automation
- built Liunx kernel level security for data security, C/C++ and Python based products

FormFactor Inc. (07/2006 to 03/2008)

Systems Analyst (On-Premise ERP Application)

Livermore, California, United States

Providing supervision, administers all aspects of an advanced, ERP/Oracle RAC system build & supporting a
specifiedfunctional area on Solaris/Linux/VMS/UNIX/ESX/Container/LDOM infrastructure environment, plan and
coordinate system utilization, and perform growth analysis and capacity planning, perform systems and
applications analysis/design and programming to produce a variety of innovative solutions to complex problems,
perform installation, maintenance, training, and user support as required; plans and coordinates projects to meet
future needs.

Advanced Network Technology Laboratories Pte Ltd (11/2001 to 05/2004) Regional Tech Support (Linux networking & security product after sales) Singapore

- APAC regional technical support for ISP customer (Linux based networking & security product)
- Remote system upgrade & License activate over SSH tunnel



Ascom Technologies (06/1995 to 02/1999) **Tech Support (Singapore Gov Computing Solution Provider)**Singapore

- Singapore Gov Computing Solution Provider (Software from UK, Mainfrain Hardware from USA)
- ProC, UNIX/HP-UX/Solaris systems, security & databases services

REFERENCE (Available on request)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-j-zhao-8656698/https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/0bf53df1d328/